[A request from Kintaro, woof!]
[Please turn on the light and keep your distance away from the television when watching the show, woof!]
Take care of the rest, Leader!
(桂)あとは頼んだぞ ﾘｰﾀﾞｰ！
武士道とは 肉球に包まれて
死ぬことと見つけたり！
I have discovered Bushido in a death surrounded by cuddly balls of flesh!
["Cat Lovers and Dog Lovers Are Mutually Exclusive."]
(猫たち)ﾆｬｰ!!
(金太郎)何してんだ ｱｲﾂ
何の引き止めにもなってねえよ｡
What's he doing?!
He's not stopping a thing!
(神楽)しかたない
かくなるうえは…｡
Guess we have no choice, then.
お前が ｴｻになるね｡
You'll just have to be the bait.
その間に 私は
じいさんのもとへ急ぐｱﾙ｡
In the meantime, I'll rush over to the old man!
(金太郎)お前が
会いに行って どうすんだ！
What good will that do?!
ｵﾚと じいさんを会わせるって
話だろうが｡
The deal was to let me meet with the old man!
ぬご！
(ｹﾞﾛｰ)ついに とらえたぞ 星喰｡
Finally got you, Planet Eater!
ﾃﾒｴは ｹﾞﾛｰ将軍！
You're...the Puke Shogun!
(ｹﾞﾛｰ)ｷｻﾏを追って
ﾉﾗ猫に身をやつし➡
I pursued you, inhabited the body of a stray cat, and lived in trash bins for years!
ｺﾞﾐ箱をあさること幾星霜！
ｷｻﾏらを駆逐すれば
我らも この体より解放される｡
By exterminating your kind, we will be released from these bodies!
くわぁ～！ 放せ！
Let go!
呪われた肉球の因果の輪
今日で断ち切ってくれる！
The curse of the balls of flesh will be broken today!
(金太郎)ぐわぁ～!!
《死ねない… ｵﾚは
まだ 死ぬわけにはいかねえ！》
I cannot die. I cannot...die yet!
そんな汚い犬に寄生したのが
ｷｻﾏの運の尽きよ｡
It was karma that made you inhabit a smelly dog!
もはや 抵抗する手段も
何もあるまい｡
It's useless to resist!
おとなしく死ぬがいい！
Resign yourself and die!
(金太郎)うっ…
なめるな ｹﾞﾛｰ将軍！
Don't take me lightly, Puke Shogun!
見るがいい 18年の年月で会得した
この絶技！
Get a taste of this ultimate technique, which I perfected over these past eighteen years!
ｷｬﾝﾄﾞﾙﾗｲﾄ ﾗｽﾄｽﾊﾟｰｷﾝｸﾞ！
Candlelight Last Sparking!
(猫たち)ﾆｬｰ!!
ただの逆上がりｱﾙ｡
ｷｬﾝﾄﾞﾙﾗｲﾄ ﾗｽﾄｽﾊﾟｰｷﾝｸﾞだ！
Looked like an ordinary flip to me.
It's the Candlelight Last Sparking!
(金太郎)まさか 役に立つとは…｡
Never thought it would come in handy.
(桂)つかぬことをお伺いするが
ここに 大きい犬と➡
This may seem like a strange question...
but did a large dog, a little dog, and a little leader pass by?
ちっちゃい犬と ちっちゃいﾘｰﾀﾞｰが
来ませんでしたか？
(看護師)知りません
ちっちゃいﾘｰﾀﾞｰって何ですか？
I don't know. What do you mean by little leader?
(桂)見た目は ちっちゃいが
器は 大きいﾘｰﾀﾞｰだ｡
Small in stature, but big in ability.
あっ やっぱ 大きいﾘｰﾀﾞｰで｡
So I guess I should say, big leader.
いや だから 知りませんって｡
Well, I don't know.
おかしいな
まだ ﾘｰﾀﾞｰ来ていないのか｡
Strange. Maybe the leader isn't here yet.
あんな異様な一団
見れば すぐに気づくはず｡
A bizarre bunch like that would attract lots of attention.
お前も異様だろ｡
(桂)まさか 肉球の手にかかって！
You're bizarre, too.
Could they have been caught by the balls of flesh?
(一郎)おい 見つかったか 次郎｡
(次郎)ﾀﾞﾒだ｡
Hey, did you find him, Jiro?
Nope.
(一郎)三郎 お前が
ちゃんと見ていないから｡
Saburo, you should have kept an eye on him!
(三郎)まさか あんな病人が
起き上がると 誰が思う？
Who'd think someone so sick could get up?!
(次郎)ｸｿｯ いったい
どこに行ったっていうんだ｡
Damn it! Where the hell would he have gone in that condition?
あんな体で｡
まさか 金太郎のところに
行ったんじゃないか｡
Could it be...
that he has gone to find Kintaro?!
(一郎)ﾊﾞｶな
あんな体でありえん…｡
That's impossible... Not in that condition.
(銀時)すみませ～ん
呼ばれて来たんですけど｡
'Scuse me. Someone called me.
(次郎)あっ あぁ 来た 来た
よろず屋さん｡
Oh, there he is.
Mr. Odd Jobs!
Hey there.
(三郎)すみません
ちょっと困ったことが起きまして｡
Sorry, but we have a problem.
あぁ!? 寄生型ｴｲﾘｱﾝの飼い主？
Huh? The master of a parasitic alien?
うむ 実は ﾘｰﾀﾞｰと➡
Yeah.
Actually, the leader and I were attempting to get the alien and the master together.
そのｴｲﾘｱﾝを 飼い主に
会わそうとしていたんだが…｡
つうか 乗せてよ！
また 面倒くさそうなことに➡
Hey, let me ride!
Got yourself involved in another messy situation, eh?
顔 突っ込みやがって｡
危篤状態と聞いていたが➡
I heard he was on his deathbed and never imagined he would leave the hospital.
まさか 病院を抜け出すとは｡
つうか 乗せてよ ねぇ
その人形 どければいいじゃん｡
Say, let me ride! Just move the doll.
ﾀﾞﾒだよ これ 神楽の代わりの
ﾒﾝﾊﾞｰだから ｽｻﾞﾝﾇ｡
No way. This is Kagura's stand-in, Suzanne.
(桂)あっ どうも 桂です｡
Oh hello, I'm Katsura.
(新八)…で 神楽ちゃんは？
そうだ！
And where's Kagura?
Oh right! The leader's being pursued by a parasitic alien and is in danger.
実は ﾘｰﾀﾞｰが 寄生型ｴｲﾘｱﾝに
追われて 危険な状態にある｡
なに!? 本当か｡
What?! Is that true?
(桂)そちらも大変そうだが
人手を貸してくれんか？
You seem to have your hands full, but will you help?
よし じゃあ ﾒﾝﾊﾞｰを分けよう｡
All right! Let's split up members.
じゃあ あと
よろしくお願いしま～す｡
All right, please take care of the rest!
(桂)よろしくな ｽｻﾞﾝﾇ｡
I'm counting on you, Suzanne.
(桂)足 引っ張らないでよね｡
Don't be a burden now.
あちこち猫だからｱﾙ｡
There are cats everywhere.
どれが 本物の猫で
どれがﾔﾂらかも わからないね｡
I can't tell which ones are real cats and which ones are those aliens.
(金太郎)うっ ｸｿｯ！
Damn it!
I exhausted my energy in that earlier scuffle, and my life gauge is down to five.
さっきのでｴﾈﾙｷﾞｰを消費して➡
寿命ｹﾞｰｼﾞが
残り５本になっちまった｡
[Life Gauge]
[Smoke one cigarette and you lose one bar.]
何ｱﾙか？
いつから そんな設定あったね？
Since when did you have that setting?
どうしてくれんだ？
残り５本で世界征服｡
Look what you did.
Now I have to conquer the world with only five bars left.
１本で 五大陸 １つずつ
征服しなきゃなんねえよ｡
That's one bar per continent.
Five is plenty in order to see the old man.
(神楽)じじいに会うには
５本で十分ね｡
(金太郎)会わねえって
言ってんだろ！ しつけえな｡
I said, I won't see him! You're so persistent!
まぁ いいｱﾙ｡
とにもかくにも➡
Well, never mind.  In any case,
薄暗いから 明かりをつけよう｡
(金太郎)どっから取ってんだ！
it's dark, so let's get some light.
Where're you taking the light from?!
What fool uses someone's life candle for lighting purposes?!
(金太郎)人の寿命ﾛｳｿｸ
明かりに使うﾔﾂがあるか！
つうか どうやったの!?
どうやって 具現化したの!?
And how the hell did you do that? How'd you materialize it just now?
ｶﾞﾀｶﾞﾀ うるさいｱﾙな！
ちゃんと私の寿命のﾛｳｿｸ 返すｱﾙ｡
Stop yammering, will ya? Here, I'll give you my life candle.
(金太郎)返せんの!?
そんなこと できるの!?
Give me...? You can do such a thing?
(神楽)ｵﾗ！ これで いいだろ｡
Here. How's that?
(金太郎)って… ものすごい勢いで
燃えてるんだけど！
Hey, it's burning so bright! Isn't this fireworks?!
これ 花火だろうが！
(神楽)たとえ 短い間でも➡
Even if it's a short life, burn hot and bright and overtake the moment.
熱く 光り輝いて 一瞬を
駆け抜けるのが 私の生き方ね｡
That's my way of life.
Who cares about your way of life! You're melting the candle next to it!
(金太郎)知らねえよ
お前の生き方なんて！
隣のﾛｳｿｸ
ｶﾞﾝｶﾞﾝ 溶かしてんだろうが！
消せ！ 今すぐ 消せ!!
Extinguish it! Put it out right now!
どんな消し方してんだ!!
Who extinguishes it like that?!
ぐわっ！
おい…
１本 よけいに消してんだろうが｡
Hey, you put an extra candle out!
Now there's only three left!  I can't breathe.
あと ３本しかねえよ！ 苦しい…｡
しっかりするね おい！ じじいに
会う前に死ぬつもりｱﾙか!?
Hey, hang on! Do you intend to die before you see the old man?!
Intend to die? It's mostly you guys who're killing me.
死ぬつもりっていうか➡
ほとんど ﾃﾒｴらに
殺されたようなもんだろうが｡
I'm not gonna see the old man. I can't let him see me like this.
じいさんとなんざ
会わねえと言ってるんだ｡
こんなﾂﾗ… 絶対に
ﾔﾂに見せるわけにはいかねえ｡
そんなに主人と会うのが ｲﾔｱﾙか？
ｲﾔだね｡
You're that adamant about not seeing your master?
Yes.
お前にとっては
ｼﾞｬﾏ者だったのかもしれない｡
Maybe he was a bother to you,
but you were also able to survive to this day because of him.
でも 今日まで
生き長らえてこられたのも➡
そのｼﾞｬﾏ者のおかげｱﾙ｡
What's wrong with seeing him just one more time?
(神楽)ひと目くらい
最後に会ってやるのも ﾀﾞﾒｱﾙか？
For him, you were a friend who sustained his lonely existence for many years.
向こうにとっては
長年の寂しい生活を➡
支えてくれた友達ｱﾙよ｡
You damn brat...
ｸｿｶﾞｷ…｡
That old man... he's not like that.
(金太郎)あのじいさんは
そんなんじゃねえんだ｡
We weren't like that.
ｵﾚたちは そんなんじゃねえんだ｡
(金太郎)この公園も よく２人で
通った お決まりの散歩ｺｰｽ…｡
We came to this park often together.
We had a set course we walked.
周りから見りゃ 老人と老犬➡
To observers, we were an old man and his old dog.
仲むつまじい光景に
見えたのかもしれねえ｡
We may've looked extremely close.
まさか 誰も くたばれなんぞと
互いに ののしり合う関係とは➡
No one could have imagined that we both wished the other would "Die!"
夢にも思わなかっただろう｡
[Kintaro]
Yeah, that was the first word he ever uttered to me.
そう… あのじいさんが 初めて
ｵﾚに言った言葉も そうだった｡
Die!
((じいさん:くたばりやがれ))
That's what the old man always said.
(金太郎)それが
じいさんの口癖だった｡
Damn you! Die!
If he didn't like something, that's what he said, no matter who it was.
気に食わないことがあると
誰彼かまわず そう言った｡
Get outta here!
To his wife, to his friends, and to me.
ばあさんにも 友人にも ｵﾚにも｡
その言葉のせいかどうかは
知らねえが➡
I don't know if that was the reason.
But one by one, the people around him died.
じいさんの周りの人間は
次々と死んでいく｡
And in time, the old man was all alone.
いつか じいさんは１人になった｡
And yet, he still kept on living.
それでも じいさんだけは
いつまで経っても くたばらない｡
((ﾃﾒｴも しぶてぇ野郎だ｡
いいかげん くたばれよ))
You're a stubborn one too. Hurry up and die.
(金太郎)そういう相手が
まだ 残っていたからだ｡
Because, he still had someone to say, "Die" to.
Kintaro...
((金太郎よ… ばあさんも死に
友人どもも みんな 死んでった｡
The old lady is gone and so are all my friends.
You're the only one left.
あとは ﾃﾒｴだけなんだよ｡
ｵﾚがな ばあさん 死んでも
子供 寄せつけず➡
Do you know why I stay away from my kids even after my wife's gone,
１人で暮らしてるわけを
教えてやろうか｡
and continue living alone?
死に顔 見られたくねえからだ｡
I don't want them to see my dying face.
今まで たくさんの死に顔
見てきたが ありゃ ﾀﾞﾒだ｡
In my time, I've seen many a dying face, but it sucks.
It's not something you can show others.
人様に見せられるもんじゃねえ｡
I'm not gonna let anyone see such a shriveled-up face. No thanks.
ｵﾚは あんなしょぼくれた顔
さらすのは ごめんだよ｡
I'm gonna die alone, unnoticed by anyone.
誰にも気づかれず １人で
ひっそり死にてぇんだよ｡
So Kintaro, hurry up and die. You're the only one left.
だから 金太郎…
さっさと くたばってくれ｡
あとは ﾃﾒｴだけなんだよ｡
ｹｯ！))
《金太郎:ﾃﾒｴが死ね！ ｸｿじじい》
You die, you old bastard!
(金太郎)ｵﾚたちは 互いに➡
We've gone on living, cursing each other to die.
くたばれ と
ののしり合い 生きていた｡
I waited for the old man to die so I could conquer Earth.
地球征服のため じいさんの死期を
待っていた ｵﾚは➡
I couldn't die, no matter what.
何があっても 死ねなかった｡
I survived, even if I had to crawl through life.
のたうち回りながらも
はいずるように 生きてきたんだ｡
しかし じいさんも生きた｡ それに
張り合うように 決して倒れない｡
But the old man kept living, too.
As if he was competing with me, he didn't fall.
No matter what illness he caught, he overcame it.
どんな病にかかろうと
必ず 戻ってきた｡
何ごともなかったように ｵﾚの前に
立ち ふてぶてしく笑ってた｡
He would stand before me as though nothing had happened, and sneer at me.
お互い 弱みも 決して見せねえ｡
We never showed each other our weaknesses.
We'd drag our weary bodies and force ourselves to go walking.
ﾖﾎﾞﾖﾎﾞの体 引きずって
ﾑﾘして 散歩にも出かけた｡
Our legs could barely move,
足なんて もう お互い
ろくに動かねえっつうのに➡
but we kept our pride and ran.
片意地張って 走った｡
支えあう気持なんて
これっぽっちもねえ｡
There wasn't a shred of feeling support for one another.
ただ お互い 相手より
１日でも １分でも １秒でも➡
All we lived for was to outlast the other by a day, a minute, even a second.
長く生きようとしてた｡
そういうﾔﾂらなんだよ ｵﾚたちは｡
That's how we are.
あのじいさんも ｵﾚと
たいして 変わりゃしねえんだ｡
The old man is no different from me.
そんなもんに会いに行って
じいさんが 喜ぶと思うか？
And you think the old man would be happy to see me?
むしろ ｵﾚを見たら➡
If he sees me, he'd get an adrenalin rush and get up again.
また張り合って
起き上がってくるに違いねえ｡
ほっとくに
こしたことは ねえんだよ｡
Leaving him alone is the best thing.
I'm sick of him, that persistent old man!
もうｳﾝｻﾞﾘなんだよ｡
あんな しつけぇ じいさん！
会いたいなんて
これっぽっちも思わねえ｡
Wanting to see him doesn't even cross my mind.
さっさと
くたばっちまえば いいんだ｡
I wish he'd hurry up and die!
(神楽)何ｱﾙか？ あれ｡
What is that?
(金太郎)あっ!? じ… じいさん！
O-Old...
...man!
Old man!
(金太郎)じいさん！
Wh-What are you doing here?! You're supposed to be on your deathbed.
な… なんで こんなところに!?
危篤状態じゃ…｡
何か持ってるｱﾙ｡
He's holding something.
(金太郎)縄…？ まさか！
A leash?
No way!
散歩…
散歩しているつもりなのか!?
A walk? He thinks he's taking a walk?!
あんな意識が はっきりしない
状態で病院から抜け出して…！
He's barely conscious, yet he left the hospital, and...
散歩を… ｵﾚとしている…｡
he's taking a walk...with me?!
き… 金太郎｡
Kintaro... I won't lose.
ｵﾚは 負けねえぞ！
ｵﾚは まだ… まだ…！
I still have...
《じ… じいさん！
なんで来やがった!?
O-Old man...why'd you come here?
あんなんなってまで
まだ ｵﾚと張り合おうってのか…｡
He's still competing with me, even in his condition?
もう やめてくれ｡
ｲﾔなんだよ ｵﾚは…｡
Enough already. I've had enough!
もうｲﾔなんだ…
わからねえのか ｸｿじじい！
Enough.
Can't you understand, you old bastard?!
ｵﾚは もうﾃﾒｴの そんな姿…》
I...I can't stand to see you like that.
Wait! Watch out!
待つｱﾙ！ 危な…！
あっ!?
(猫)ﾆｬｰｵ！
I found you. I found you, Planet Eater!
見つけた！ 見つけたぞ！ 星喰｡
(猫)もう逃がさん！
ｷｻﾏら 悪しき存在｡
You can't escape now.
You are an evil presence.
一片の塵も残さず 宇宙より
消し去ってくれるわ～!!
We will erase each and every one of you...
...from the universe!
あっ!?
Y-You!
あっ！
おっ… お前！
ふぬ～！
(猫たちの鳴き声)
あっ！
(神楽)うっ！
(神楽)早く！
Hurry!
早く行くｱﾙ！
Hurry and go!
(神楽)散歩… いつまで１人で
やらせるつもりｱﾙか！
How long must he walk alone?!
I'm not telling you to say good-bye.
さようならなんて言えとは
言わないｱﾙ！
くたばれって言ってこいよ！
Go tell him to die.
最後まで隣で ののしって
隣で張り合って➡
Curse and rant at him until the very end.
Stay and fight with him.
隣で くたばってこいよ！
Stay and die with him!
うおりゃ～!!
(神楽)それでいいﾈ お前たちは｡
それが お前たちｱﾙ｡
And that'll do...for you two.
That's what you two are.
(ｹﾞﾛｰ)この期に及んで
まだ我らのｼﾞｬﾏ立てをするのか!!
You're still going to get in our way?!
(神楽)うっ!? あっ！
This one is trying to destroy this planet!
(ｹﾞﾛｰ)そやつは
この星を滅ぼさんとする存在だ｡
これに くみするは
ｷｻﾏも星に仇なす者と みなすぞ！
If you defend him, we'll consider you a danger to this planet, too!
(神楽)地球制服なんて
いくらｼﾞｬﾏしようと構わない！
I don't care what you do to stop the conquest of Earth.
でも ﾜﾝ公には➡
But there's two things we mustn't interfere with when it comes to this dog.
２つだけ 絶対
ｼﾞｬﾏしちゃいけないものがあるﾈ！
That's the time to eat and the time to take a walk!
ｴｻと散歩の時間ｱﾙ!!
(猫たちの鳴き声)
Shogun! Our offensive isn't working at all!
(猫)将軍！ 我々の攻撃が
まったく刃が立ちません！
What's with that girl's fighting strength?!
(ｹﾞﾛｰ)なんだ あの娘の戦闘力は！
星喰以上の驚異だ！
She's even stronger than the Planet Eater!
うぬ…！ ｵﾒｶﾞを呼べ!!
Summon Omega!
(猫)ｵﾒｶﾞを!? 危険すぎます！
Omega?! It's too dangerous!
そんなこと言ってる
場合ではない！
This is no time to be saying that!
新たなる星の驚異
見逃すわけにはいかぬ！
She is another threat to the planet! We must not let her escape!
＜寄生腫 ｵﾒｶﾞ｡
Parasite Omega.
それは星吐のなかでも
屈指の実力をもつ➡
Even among Planet Pukers, it had superior strength and was known as the Sweeper.
ｽｲｰﾊﾟｰとよばれる存在であった｡
星喰と星吐が➡
Omega was born from the power of alcohol in a cross-fertilization of Planet Eaters and Planet Pukers,
酒の勢いで
交配して生まれた ｵﾒｶﾞは➡
and was the ultimate warrior possessing the strengths of both.
まさしく
両者の能力を兼ね備えた➡
超戦士だったが
しかし同時に精神的に不安定で➡
However, at the same time, it was psychologically unstable,
ときに星喰に匹敵する
凶暴性をみせた＞
and could go into a frenzy that matched the Planet Eaters.
≪将軍 ﾍﾀをすれば
この星も我々も滅びます！
Shogun, if we're not careful, this planet could be destroyed with us on it!
あの 新たな脅威を➡
That's the risk we must take in order to stop this new menace!
ここで食い止めるためには
それも やむをえん！
ｷｻﾏらも これで終わりだ！
It's over for you guys!
ｵﾒｶﾞよ！
すべてを焼き尽くすがいい！
Omega! Burn everything in sight!
Hello, I'm Omemi. Nice to meet you.
(桂)こんにちは 私 ｵﾒ美｡
みんな よろしくね｡
ほぁちゃゃ～！
いよいよ お迎えが ちけえか｡
So, my time is near, eh?
猫が 空を飛んでやがら …ふがぁ｡
I can see cats flying through the air.
ぐふっ｡
ぐあぁぁ ﾛｳｿｸが…！
The candles. Two of my life candles have been broken!
寿命のﾛｳｿｸが ２本折れたぁ！
もう １本しかねえ｡
I only have one left!
《金太郎:なんてことしやがんだ
あの ｱﾏ！》
What the hell is she doing?!
行け 早く！
Go! Hurry!
《金太郎:散歩だと…!?
ふざけやがって｡
A walk?! Is she crazy?
もう そんなもん
できる状態じゃねえんだよ｡
I'm way past being able to do that!
た… 立つことも ままならねえ｡
I-I can't even stand.
じいさんも今ので
完全に ﾛｳｿｸ全部もってかれ…｡
The old man's candle was probably snuffed out just now!
じじいぃぃ!!
Old man!
な… なんだと!?
What?! There's only one candle left, and he's standing!
もう ﾛｳｿｸ１本しかねえのに
立ち上がりやがった！》
ﾌﾍﾍﾍ… き 金太郎｡
Kintaro, so you're finally at death's doorstep? How pitiful!
いよいよ ﾃﾒｴもしめえか!?
情けねえ野郎だ｡
ｵﾚは まだ ﾋﾟﾝﾋﾟﾝしてるぜ!?
I'm still fit as a fiddle. If you're unable to take a walk, it's over for a human.
散歩もできなくなっちゃ
人間 しめえだよ｡
じじいは
さっさと くたばっちめえな！
Old geezers should hurry and die!
んっ!?
《金太郎:ﾅ… ﾅﾒんじゃねえ
ｸｿじじい！
D-Don't take me lightly, you damn bastard!
ｵﾚは まだやれる｡
I've still got it. I'll never lose to an old geezer like you!
あんな老いぼれに
絶対負けねえ！》
ｸｸｸ… ﾑﾘしちゃいけねえよ｡
Hey, don't force yourself.
知ってんだぜ ﾃﾒｴが
もう 死にかけてるってことは｡
I know... that you're already half-dead.
《金太郎:そりゃ ﾃﾒｴもだろうが》
Same goes for you.
(じいさん)
ほ… 本当に しぶてえ野郎だ！
What a stubborn dog.
《金太郎:ｸｿじじい…
くたばりやがれ！
Damn old buzzard! Die!
…頼むから》
Please...
Die!
((じいさん:くたばりやがれ｡
Dear, what a thing to say!
(ばあさん)ちょっと
ｱﾝﾀ なんてこと言うんですか｡
That pup's mother and siblings died after a difficult birth and it's all alone.
そのこ えらく難産で
産まれてすぐに➡
母親も兄弟も
死んじゃったのよ｡
(じいさん)だからいっそ➡
That's why I'm saying it should've died, too!
ｺｲﾂも 死んじまえばよかったと
言ってるんだ｡
And I'm saying that's a mean thing to say!
(ばあさん)
それが ﾋﾄﾞｲって言ってんの｡
ｱﾝﾀは もう｡
ひでぇ もんかい！
That's not mean at all!
What's mean is the mother and the siblings dying, leaving him all alone.
本当に ひでぇのは
ｺｲﾂを残して死んでいったﾔﾂらよ｡
死んでくﾔﾂらより➡
It's way harder being the one left behind.
残された者のほうが
よっぽど つれえもんさ｡
ｺｲﾂが じいさんになって
死ぬときまで➡
I don't have the confidence to live long enough until he's old and dies.
ｵﾚは 生きてる自信がねえ｡
ｺｲﾂを またひとり➡
If he's gonna be left all alone again, it would've been better if he had died, too.
残してくくれえなら
いっそ 死んじまったほうが➡
よかったのかもしれねえ
そう言ってるんだ｡
That's the point I'm making.
私が いるじゃないのさ｡
I'm here.
ｵﾚが お前より先に
死ぬわけねえだろ！
There's no way I'll die before you!
I'm ten years younger than you.
(ばあさん)私のほうが
10若いんですよ｡
(じいさん)
女は ｱﾃになりゃしねえや｡
You can never depend on a woman.
ｵﾚとお前じゃ 覚悟が違うんだ｡
You and I have different resolves.
…なぁ おい ｵﾚはよ
あいにく こんなじいさんだ｡
Hey, you... Unfortunately, I'm an old man.
ﾃﾒｴの 母親代わりにも
兄弟にもなれねえ｡
I can't be a surrogate mom or brother to you. But I can be your buddy.
だが ﾀﾞﾁ公にならなれる｡
ﾌｯ… ﾀﾞﾁ公は いいぞ！
Buddies are great. Age, sex, family, relationships don't matter.
歳も性別も種族も関係ねえ｡
愛人は １人でもいりゃ
嫁さんにｼﾊﾞかれるが➡
If you have a lover, your wife'll beat you up.
友人は何人つくろうが
文句を言うﾔﾂは いねえ｡
But you can have as many friends as you like and no one'll complain.
だが それゆえに
ｵﾚは掟を ひとつだけ設けてんだ｡
But because of it, I go by a single rule.
相手より先に 死なねえことさ｡
Don't die before your friend.
あちこち友人こさえて
おっ死んで➡
I hate it when you have lots of friends here and there,
大勢を泣かせるようなﾏﾈは
ｵﾚは 嫌いだ｡
and you go and die and make them all sad.
だったら ひとりになるまで
生き残って ひとりで泣く｡
So, you live until you're all alone and you cry alone.
You watch them all die, then you die alone.
死に顔 全部見届けて
ひとりで 死ぬ｡
ｵﾚが泣くことはあっても
ﾀﾞﾁ公だけは泣かせねえよ｡
Even if I cry, I'll never make a buddy cry.
That's my rule when making a friend.
それが ｵﾚが ﾀﾞﾁ公をつくるときの
掟だ… 安心しろ｡
So rest assured. You'll never need to cry because you're all alone.
お前は もう一人になる
ことになって泣くこともねえ｡
お前が死んだら ｵﾚが泣いてやる｡
After you die, I'll cry for you.
だから 安心してくたばれ ﾀﾞﾁ公))
So rest assured and die, buddy.
《ｸｿじじい もう いいってんだ｡
You old bastard, enough already.
もう十分だってんだ｡
That's enough...
もう やめてくれ… 頼むから｡
Stop...please.
さっさと くたばってくれ｡
Hurry and die...
見たかねえんだ｡
もう見たかねえんだ｡
I don't want to see... I don't want to see you...
ﾃﾒｴが無理して
苦しんでる姿なんて➡
hanging in there and suffering.
ｵﾚは もう見たかねえんだよ！》
I don't want to see it anymore!
(ｹﾞﾛｰ)ﾊﾊﾊ… 逃がさんぞ 星喰！
You won't get away, Planet Eater!
(ｹﾞﾛｰ)お前が死ねば
星喰の殲滅は完了する｡
If you die, the extermination of Planet Eaters will be over.
さすれば この肉体より
我らは解放され➡
Then we will be released from this body of flesh.
寄生する対象を変えて➡
We'll change our parasite hosts and eradicate those beasts!
あの化け物たちを
改めて排除するだろう｡
ﾌﾌﾌ！ これで 我らの勝…｡
It's our victo--!
あっ… あれ？ あれ？
Huh? Huh? Huh?!
ちょ… これ引けな…！
あれ？ あれぇ!?
I can't fire! Huh? Huh?!
(ｹﾞﾛｰ)って あれぇぇ!?
Huh?!
あれ… 今 なんかやっちゃった？
やっちゃいましたね｡
Hey, did I just do something?
I think you did.
《会いにいかずにいれば➡
I thought that if I didn't go to see him, he could die in peace.
楽に死んでくれるだろうと
思ってたのに…➡
なんで出てきやがった｡
Why'd he come here? Was it just to suffer?
わざわざ苦しみにきたってのか｡
ｵﾚが死ねば 楽になるのだろう｡
If I die, you'll be at peace, right?
ｵﾚが先に死にゃ
ｱﾝﾀも安心して死ぬのだろう｡
If I die first, you'll be at peace and can die too, right?
だけどよう もうそりゃ
できそうにねえや じいさん｡
But, I don't think we can do that anymore, old man.
ｵﾚは ｱﾝﾀより先には
絶対 死ぬわけにはいかねえよ｡
I can't die before you die.
ったく ｵﾚも ﾔｷが回ったもんだぜ｡
Damn, I'm starting to lose it, old man.
じいさん ｵﾚはよ いつの間にか
恐怖の大王なんかより➡
I don't know when it happened, but more than being the King of Terror...
ﾃﾒｴのﾀﾞﾁ公になりたく
なっちまってたんだよ｡
I've wanted to be your buddy.
だから ｱﾝﾀ 泣かせるわけにゃ
いかねえんだよ！
So I can't make you cry!
なのに なんで
くたばらねえ じいさん｡
So, why don't you hurry up and die, old man?!
くたばってくれ じいさん！
Die, old man!
頼むから くたばってくれよ！
Please die!
じいさん くたばれ！
くたばってくれ！》
Old man, die! Die!
Die! You old bastard!
《くたばりやがれ ｸｿじじい！》
♪♪～
(じいさん)き… 金太郎よ
ｵﾚの勝ちだぜ…｡
K-Kintaro...
I win.
ﾃﾒｴは… ﾀﾞﾁ公 泣かしたからな｡
Because you...made your buddy cry.
(じいさん)ありがとうよ… ﾀﾞﾁ公｡
Th-Thanks...
Buddy...
(神楽)定春 行くｱﾙよ！
(定春)ﾜﾝ！
Sadaharu, let's go.
♪♪～
The next episode:
"Fights Often Ensue During Trips"
[Around this time last year we had to skip an episode because of the Japan Series. And this year...]
[We're Not Skipping!]